<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Miles Hilliard</title>
    <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Miles Hilliard</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:03:04 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mileshilliard.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Robotics &amp; Engineering - Week of 1/6/25</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/1-6-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 13:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/1-6-25/</guid>
      <description>While in robotics this week, I continued my work on the lightbox project. This week involved a lot of CAD and 3D printing for me, and ended up taking a bit more time than expected. Generally speaking, I am ahead of schedule so I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry too much.&#xA;The light box is composed of two main parts that get 3D printed and screwed together. There is the base which is the outer shell and holds the button and power jack.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GUI over SSH with X11</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/gui-over-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 13:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/gui-over-ssh/</guid>
      <description>SSH is awesome, but your options when trying to run a GUI application are a bit limited, especially on headless computers. Luckily there are a few ways to go about handling this problem, even if your computer has no monitor directly connected to it.&#xA;SSH into the machine First of all, you need to ssh into your machine to get everything set up. Now you have a couple options. Some people may have a display (be it a full monitor, a TV screen, a touch display, etc) and others may have nothing it all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Robotics &amp; Engineering - Week of 12/16/24</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/12-16-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 13:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/12-16-24/</guid>
      <description>During my time in the Robotics Shop 5th and 6th period this week, I made significant headway on the lightbox project. For my lightbox, I will be making a transparent &amp;ldquo;EXIT&amp;rdquo; sign that you frequently see in modern office buildings. These signs are very expensive and can be found online for hundreds of dollars. My plan is to make it for much less. The most expensive component to the project would be the acrylic, which can be found for about 10 dollars for an appropriate size.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baofeng UV5R DIY direct to computer audio cable</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/uv5r-audio-pc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 10:28:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/uv5r-audio-pc/</guid>
      <description>With my new HAM radio license in the books, I bought the Baofeng UV5R as my first HT. Between its low-cost and various features, I think its been a great radio to start out with. With an upgraded antenna (almost not optional) and a larger battery bank, I&amp;rsquo;ve found the radio to be a pretty solid unit. Unfortunately, there is no direct way to plug in the radio&amp;rsquo;s speaker and mic jacks to a computer soundcard to transmit and receive sounds to and from my PC, but with a simple cable modification, this can be done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing OpenCV on RPi in 2024</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/rpi-cv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 13:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/rpi-cv2/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Between all the various tutorials online, there is no straight way to installing OpenCV on a RPI&amp;hellip;&#xA;Issue&amp;rsquo;s I have encountered personally include but are not limited to the following:&#xA;Building from source issues Various rare errors Garbage tutorials So in this simple guide, I have documented my installation of OpenCV on my Raspberry Pi, Model 3 B+&#xA;Other models should be quite similar.&#xA;Requirements For this project, I used a Raspberry Pi 3 B+ running Ubuntu Server 20.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI Meets the Deep: Our Journey to 3rd Place in the 2024 Exploration Challenge</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/noaa-ocean-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2024 13:03:04 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/noaa-ocean-exploration/</guid>
      <description>With the annual MATE ROV competition all finished up, Sunk Robotics placed 3rd worldwide in terms of robotics, and 9th overall including the marketing and advertising campaigns. A good run indeed. Our robot performed well, although reliability is our priority for next year’s attempt.&#xA;A New Competition Although MATE ROV offers its well-known underwater competition, there are other events they host as well. This year, Matty Harris and I undertook a secondary challenge, known as the 2024 Ocean Exploration Video Challenge (OER) where teams must create custom Artificial Intelligence models that can be used to identify underwater species from a provided video.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to Oracle Cloud servers with VNC</title>
      <link>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/vnc-oci/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:58:51 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.mileshilliard.com/posts/vnc-oci/</guid>
      <description>Oracle Cloud is a cloud computing service offered by Oracle Corporation. It provides a range of cloud services, including:&#xA;Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS): This includes virtual machines, storage, and networking resources. Platform as a Service (PaaS): Offers tools for developing, managing, and deploying applications, including databases, application development, and integration services. Software as a Service (SaaS): Provides ready-to-use software applications hosted in the cloud, such as enterprise resource planning (ERP), human capital management (HCM), and customer relationship management (CRM) applications.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
